what's up everybody this is Nick at
bobbend.com and today I'm talking to you
about the best supplements for muscle
growth what are you trying to pack on
some muscle for aesthetic reasons or
you're looking to get some hypertrophy
into your strength training Alex muscle
is a good Valiant valuable and
noteworthy thing to do with your time
with your life don't let anyone tell you
otherwise and we've got a wide range of
supplements here that can help to
promote muscle growth be it a protein
powder that fits into your macro goals a
pre-workout to help you push harder in
the gym or a post workout to help you
recover more quickly the supplement for
you is here on this list so definitely
stick around we're gonna be going
through a whole range of categories and
also going into what to look for when
you are trying to gain some muscle so
stick around to find out which one is
best for you and your individual goals
foreign
[Music]
I do have to make it clear for a few
reasons I'm not a medical adductor this
is not medical information before you
are making any changes to your
supplement nutrition exercise regimen or
about anything else touch your doctor so
they can squirt away with you your
personal history medications and so on
now before I give you a little guide on
the kinds of muscle building supplements
out there so you have an idea of like
what to look for in the areas in which
you can look for supplements I'm just
going to do what a lot of YouTubers
don't do I'm just going to tell you what
our number one pick is in this whole
video because that's probably why you
clicking this video the number one
supplement for muscle building get ready
this one's gonna shock you it's protein
everyone who wants to build muscle will
do well to have a protein powder is it
100 necessary no but is protein the most
difficult to get most expensive most
inconvenient and perhaps most important
macronutrient when you're trying to gain
muscle uh yeah this whey protein from
Wolverine's Wolverine whey protein
isolate has such fantastic protein per
calorie that it's about the same as
getting chicken breast but it's faster
it's cheaper and it is more delicious
let's be honest and again to all the
reasons why we landed on this particular
branch in a second but first
what's a muscle building supplement
there are a few different kinds of
supplements to look at for muscle
building each will help in their own way
first up protein I kind of just did the
whole Spiel of our protein powder but it
doesn't have to be way protein though
there are many kinds of approaching out
there there are even many kinds of whey
protein itself like there's way
concentrate on isolate hydraulic set but
we are also going to mention some
plant-based proteins in this video then
there's pre-workouts right now the most
important thing about any supplement
when it comes to building muscle is is
it going to help you do more reps or do
more work right all the talk about you
know this increases blood flow and this
increases power output this increases
Focus that's all nice whatever helps you
to get more work done in the gym will
lead to more muscle growth like that's
the that's the most important component
of that puzzle when it comes to
pre-workout supplementation so we got
pre-workout on this list as well and
then there's creatine which is a common
pre-workout ingredient but you don't
actually have to take it pre-workout you
can just take it any time of day it's
not a stimulant and taking five grams a
day for about four weeks saturates the
muscles and then you're getting the
benefits of creatine the other thing to
you think about with creatine is that it
also has a real aesthetic benefit in
that it draws more water into the
muscles making them bigger they look
bigger right about 20 of people don't
respond to creatine but like overall
people really like the aesthetic
benefits of creatine they'll say they're
doing it for the power they're doing it
because it makes their muscles look
bigger but both are very good effects to
have from creatine the last one to
mention is branched chain amino acids
these are not quite as popular as they
used to be when people thought it was
just going to add slabs and slabs of
muscle to your body for zero calories
but branched amino acids do is they are
three building blocks of protein and the
ones that are closely linked to muscle
protein synthesis so the main goal with
branched chain amino acids these days
the main reason people take them is that
if you're going a long time without
eating any protein or you're fasting or
you're working on an empty stomach or
your protein intake is low for the day
taking branched 10 amino acids may help
to retain more muscle than you would
otherwise right because it's got there's
leucine in there and isolucine and
valine and that appears to help
stimulate muscle protein synthesis there
is more to the muscle gain puzzle and
you know what another talk about the
supplements of muscle gain the most
important takeaway for beginning muscle
is your total calories and
macronutrients also your workouts also
your sleep all of this is vastly vastly
vastly important stuff so these
supplements here though they'll help to
potentially Shore up any holes in that
plant and make the whole thing run a
little bit more smoothly but make sure
you look at your calories first
[Music]
all right so to reiterate what that top
spot is the best overall muscle building
supplement is protein and our favorite
whey protein powder is Wolverine's whey
protein isolate there are a few reasons
allowed on this particular protein the
main one is it's got really high protein
per calorie right because of the Whey
Protein Isolate really there are two
kinds of work there's whey concentrate
which is the cheapest form of whey and
there's way isolate which is in
processed from way concentrate to strip
out all of the carbohydrates sugar
lactose and fat so basically both are
very high in protein per calorie weight
isolate is preferable to a lot of folks
because it's simply denser in protein
and also if you have like lactose
sensitivities it's possible that it
might be easier for you to digest
because it's lower in lactose so we
really like the way you isolate here
there's a ludicrous 26 grams of protein
for one gram of carbohydrates and half a
gram of fat in this flavor the flavor is
honey cinnamon peanut butter which is
absolutely delicious interestingly it's
naturally flavored although it does have
an artificial sweetener if that's a big
deal for you and also the other reason
why we really like this one as our best
way protein powder overall that it
contains digestive enzymes so you're
getting caffeine and protease here and
those enzymes could help to improve
absorption of the protein itself there
are a couple studies out there that you
can look at that have found that when
someone has enzymes like these with
their whey protein powder they've
measured like more amino acids in the
bloodstream more quickly so in other
words you're kind of getting more bang
for your buck like you're absorbing and
digesting more of the protein when you
have enzymes with it according to some
research anyway so enzymes can also
sometimes make them digest a little more
easily like if regular whey is a bit
tough to digest whatever reason
sometimes adding in enzymes can help too
uh speak to doctor if you have concerns
about you know indigestion and
everything but yeah we there's a lot of
reasons to like whey protein powder that
has enzymes in it plus given how much
protein per calorie this has uh yeah we
consider this to be the best way I sleep
on the market and the best supplement
for muscle building
[Music]
foreign
for muscle growth right here it is huge
supplements
creatine why do we go this creatine
because it's just regular old creatine
there have been hundreds and hundreds
and hundreds and hundreds of studies on
Creatine monohydrates all the other
creatines except for creatine
hydrochloride the other ones one or two
studies each get creatine monohydrate
this one here it's uh just regular
crease I'm going to Hydra it's
unflavored and creatine does not have a
taste or anything so it's really nice
you can even dry scoop it sometimes I do
and I absolutely have to I don't have a
shaker cup five grams of creatine wanna
hydrate per scoop here it comes with a
scoop which is also nice because uh
there were years there when basically no
one was including a five gram scoop up
with their creatine which was an
annoying way to dose so there you go
it's playing creation you want to
hydrate it's unflavored and that is
absolutely all you need from your
creatine so that's why we said that huge
supplements is the best creating now
before I go on I want to make it clear
we have a written version of this video
because I understand that I'm throwing a
lot of information at you uh and it's
cool we're talking about so many
different areas of supplementation as
well like there's even for one of our
supplement videos there's a lot going on
here so there's a written version of
this article if you want to check that
out so just go to Google but in
Broadband best supplements and muscle
growth it'll come right up and then if
you want to go through this all at your
own pace and like have a look at the
nutrition labels yourself uh it'll all
be there for you so there you go head
over to Google if you want for now let's
move on to the next pick
next up we've got the best pre-workout
for muscle gain and it has got to be
erect from huge supplements it is an
extraordinarily potent pre-workout now
pre-workouts that can probably make or
break your supplement routine for
gaining muscle right like I mean protein
would be the most important
um creatine does a lot too but as I said
earlier it's whatever helps you to
perform better in the gym is the most
important kind of pre-workout that's
going to be caffeine most of the time
and the first question you're probably
asking is how much caffeine is in this
350 milligrams now a 12 ounce cold brew
from like the average coffee shop is
about 155 milligrams so this is well
over two 12 ounce coffees right like
like a lot more than that what's
interesting though is that you're
getting 250 milligrams of caffeine and
hydrous and then 100 milligrams of
caffeine diamalate caffeine Diet malate
digests more slowly like it gets into
the bloodstream more slowly so the idea
here is that while this is an an
extraordinary amount of caffeine it's
not meant to have the same Spike and
then crash that can sometimes accompany
that sort of amount of caffeine right
like it's meant to sort of come on a bit
more slowly anticipate a bit more slowly
as well there's also some other
ingredients here that can help with
focus and potentially reduce the Jitters
that sometimes accompany a big hit of
caffeine like l-tyrosine and then
there's all the other ingredients that
I've kind of mentioned at the beginning
of this video that are popular in
pre-workout so we've got better in
anhydrous that comes from beets there's
also citrulline in here this is a nice
dosage of eight grams a lot of
pre-workers out there they'll just
include one gram and say look we have
citrulline but it won't reach the
minimum effective dose suggested by the
literature which is like a good five
grams uh plenty more ingredients here I
don't want to slow down this video too
much getting to all the details with
this one suffice to say it's a very long
ingredients list there are ingredients
for endurance power blood flow Focus
there's even an adaptogen in here which
can help the body to adapt to stress
like it's a very interesting area of
supplementation there's like some lines
made Mushroom in here for that it's very
unusual to find in a pre-workout but
everything is very strong like very
clinically dosed very effectively doors
unlike a lot of prerequisites on the
market so the best pre-workout thought
muscle group is this one right here
wrecked from huge supplements
[Music]
next up the best post-workout supplement
for muscle gain our pick for that one is
caged re-caged so the post-workout
window is an interesting one in the in
the research in like the 90s everyone
was positive that you had to Sprint to
your whey protein powder as fast as
possible the second your workout ends to
make sure you're feeding your muscles or
the amino acids that they need and
there's like a window through which
you're going to get the most muscle
again right what actually matters the
most is your overall calories and
macronutrients at the end of the day
then the timing that's important and if
any timing does matter it's probably
pre-workout re-caged here it doesn't
have the carbohydrates what that really
means though is that this can fit well
into a low carb or a low-fat diet plan
it's just really very high in protein so
protein like whether you're in low fat
or low carb you do need a considerable
amount of protein and so to send some
helpful amino acids over to your muscles
one serving of this post-workout formula
has 140 calories so you're 28 grams of
protein just two grams of carbohydrates
and one gram of fat what else this has
besides protein are just some
ingredients that you might commonly find
in pre-workouts but but not the caffeine
right so the main ingredient for this
one is beta in anhydrous which I
mentioned earlier has some potential
effects on the power output
interestingly it's not really a
pre-workout ingredient in that you can
actually take it any time of day and a
lot of the research on it has people
taking two doses throughout the day so
this can be like a good second dose of
it in anhydrous the other stuff in here
there's a bit of glutamine which used to
be more common in muscle building
supplements but there is nonetheless
some evidence to suggest that uh it may
be helpful in uh in building new tissue
in the body and also it has some
implications for gut health as well why
not and then speaking of gut health this
also has a digestive enzyme blend of
prohydrolase which is like a blend of
proteases creation hydrochloride betting
anhydrous mixture power a bit of
glutamine for potentially some extra
help building tissue you also got the
enzymes to help break down all the
protein and then Protein that's re-caged
and that's our favorite post workout
foreign
[Music]
for muscle growth our favorite
supplement for it is Wolverines beta
alanine because it's nothing but beta
Alanis uh this is unflavored you can mix
into any kind of drink you want and
there's no extra ingredients whatsoever
right it's 100 better alanine it's a
non-essential amino acid by the way a
couple things you should know about beta
alanine uh the research on it is usually
on it's in the endurance realm like if
it's doing strength training it's on
strength endurance so that's typically
the finest in the 10 to 20 rep range
that's where you're going to get the
most benefits for better ironing uh
there was a study I believe it was in
the general amino acids and there's been
a couple of them now that have found the
benefit to be it was 2.85 in performance
in uh in high level Insurance activities
right and so if you're a high level
athlete like an almost three percent
Advantage is actually very very very
significant so it is one of the more
research pre-workout ingredients but
another thing to know about that alanine
is you don't have to take a pre-workout
like beta in anhydrous can take it
anytime the effects sort of it's not
like they accumulate you know what I
mean so if you've had it at any point
like the last 24 hours it should help
the normal dose is minimum 1.6 grams uh
a lot of the time the studies on it have
put the doses up more like three grams
uh this five grams per serving here and
it's also just 100 better online so if
you want to have more you can talk to
your doctor first the last thing to
mention about beta alanine helps with
endurance Health performance in that way
you can do more work in that way it
helps you to build more muscle it's
extremely common and extremely beloved
by people in the supplement world but it
does produce
typically a tingling sensation on the
skin is called paresthesia it is
temporary it's completely harmless some
people like it it feels like they're
like really cutting into the wolf band
like my pre-workout's kicking in when
you hear people say that they're
generally talking about that tingling
sensation beta alanine our favorite bed
element product for muscle growth and
just you know in general is uh soberings
next up the best beta aim supplement for
muscle growth this is Formula 12 from
huge supplements and when scoop has
three grams of bedding very solid amount
this one here is actually typically used
or at least marketed as a post-worker
formula or an intra workout formula like
something to drink during a workout the
reason for that is it's got a lot of
ingredients again that you get in
pre-workouts that aren't necessarily
time bound right so you get the beta in
but you've also got better alanine as
well and a few others there's also a
good amount of antioxidants in this so
like there's grape seed extract and
alpha lipoic acid these are ingredients
along with a couple others here that are
a good source of antioxidants so in that
regard they can potentially help to
mitigate inflammation and muscle
soreness like help a little bit in that
regard and then lastly the other thing I
want to mention is there's a few grams
of carbohydrates in this not very much
but they're the kinds of carbs that
people tend to get excited about in the
realm of muscle building so what we've
got here is a mod carb and clustered
deck screen and like you know this is
not a very high carbohydrate product I
think it's like less than 15 grams of
carbohydrates per scoop 20 grams Max but
these types of carbohydrates that digest
very quickly and they can like avoid
like a bloated sort of feeling with your
carbohydrate intake so yeah a lot of
people they get interested in cluster
dextrin as a source of carbohydrates
plus you get the beta eat and everything
else and this is still overall very very
low calorie so it's functionally an
ergogenic supplement with a little bit
of carbohydrates to us like Spike
insulin to help with nutrient absorption
like you know reduce bloating that sort
of thing and it's also plenty of better
in there as well so this is our favorite
beta in supplement for muscle growth
particularly because it's got a good
dosage of beta in and because there are
several other ingredients in there that
can through Myriad ways potentially help
with muscle growth too next up we have
the best branched chain amino acid
supplement for muscle growth our
favorite is on its total strength and
performance we just ran out of it we're
waiting for a new one to come in it
looks like this though we're big fans of
this one on it if you uh if you know
much about the supplement game you've
probably heard of on it you probably
have some things associated with on it
mainly they have like a really
interestingly kind of holistic approach
to supplementation and Fitness on the
fitness side they've got a lot of kettle
stuff mace stuff unbalanced stuff like
they move a lot in the transverse plane
that sort of thing and with the
supplements they like to lean a lot on
natural ingredients and natural products
right so what you like about the
branches amino acids supplement from on
it called total strength and performance
blend is that in addition to having a
nice dose of the three branched chain
amino acids that I've already kind of
talked about and told what they do
already like four times in this video
besides that it's got some beta alanine
which we've also talked about but it's
also got a whole range of plant extracts
as well and also some diaspatic acid and
if you look into the research Behind
These plant extracts it appears that the
main goal of on it here is to help to
maximize the software and minimize
estrogen as much as a natural supplement
can so this isn't going to reach the
height of like you know getting
testosterone replacement therapy but if
you look at the research Behind These
like plant-based extracts there is some
interesting research suggesting they can
help to like neutralize or lower
estrogen and increase testosterone
temporarily right so it's not going to
totally like make or break your toes
free testosterone count but they're
pretty cool ingredients I encourage you
to check out the full written version of
this video as well because we go into a
bit more of the science then you can see
the ingredients we're talking about so
honestylescent performance Bland good
amount of Branch chain amino acids
you've got a better alanine as well for
performance a wide array of plant
extracts that could potentially help
with hormones and it's naturally
flavored and sweetened as well so you
don't have to worry about any artificial
sweetness or anything like that
relax
[Music]
next up we've got the best vegan protein
for muscle growth we're going back to
our friends at small Vereen because we
just we just like the supplements man
and this one here is Wolverine's plant
protein and what we like about this and
I mentioned this in the introduction uh
it is pretty hard to get a vegan protein
powder that isn't pretty high in carbs
or fat because the protein typically
comes from high carb legumes or high fat
seeds but the amounts of process this in
such a way that although the base of it
is pea protein and pumpkin protein the
calories are pretty close to what you
get in like a whey concentrate so it is
22 grams of protein for three grams of
carbohydrates and two and a half grams
of fat which is really high in protein
per calorie especially for a vegan
protein especially if you were alive in
the 90s and saw the kind of vegan
proteins were coming out back then this
is a pretty impressive feat what's also
cool about this is they've added in some
extra nutrition so you're getting like
32 of your daily iron which is like it's
always good to get a bit of extra iron
when you're on a plant-based diet or
you're just not eating a lot of meat
because also plenty of B vitamins and a
bit of chromium as well the last couple
things I want to mention here the
protein per calorie is very good this is
all natural there's no artificial
flavors or sweeteners there's no soy
which some people try to limit and also
the pea protein here I encourage you to
do a bit of research on the amino acid
profile of pee right like the pumpkin
here helps to shore up any deficiencies
in other amino acids but pea protein is
really famously very very high in
leucine which is the amino acid that a
whey protein is kind of known for and
it's the one that's most closely
associated with muscle protein synthesis
so we really like the form of protein
they've chosen here the fact that it's
all natural as well because a lot of
plant-based folks I know also try to
avoid artificial flavors and sweeteners
and stuff and also the potion about
calorie is very impressive for a vegan
protein as well so that's vegan protein
for muscle building Sovereign
[Music]
all right let's talk about citrulline I
touched this earlier very common
pre-workout ingredient links to blood
fluoro power put studies on cyclists
tennis players you know all about
citrulline what's the best citrulline
supplement for maintaining muscle growth
we think it's this one from on it it's
got a big nitric oxide on the front of
it and that is because nitric oxide is
something you hear a lot about when it
comes to like pre-workout supplements
and general supplements for blood flow
because ingredients like citrulline and
also like beetroot powder and quite a
few other ones that have this uh blood
flow vasodilation angle to them what
they do is they help to stimulate the
body's production of nitric oxide so it
increases nitric oxide in the blood and
that is what signals to our blood
vessels to dilate this nitric oxide
supplement we really like it it does
have citrulline in it but it also has
some extra curious ingredients that are
also linked to nitric oxide production
which for most folks is the goal of
taking citrulline in the first place and
it's yours as well if you clicked on
best citrulline supplement for muscle
growth right so like they've got a blend
here they've got the Stitch lean they've
also got some Arginine which has similar
effects to citrulline they've also got
fermented beetroot which is famously
it's more effective than regular padded
beetroot as well for one it's simulated
nitric oxide production number two
beetroot is the most potent source of
nitrate for increasing nitric oxide
production so if you Google like
beetroot powder benefits like if you go
to studies that aren't beetroot powder
they're all on like athletes taking
beetroot powder to stimulate blood flow
and increase nitric oxide production
beets very very cool so if you're
looking for a citrulline supplement your
goal is almost certainly to increase
blood flow and increase your pump for
that you want to increase your nitric
oxide production citrulline house but so
does the beat here fermented bit is
better at doing it the arganine also
helps and there are also a few extra
ingredients in here that are pretty
strong antioxidant sources meaning that
they can potentially help with recovery
as well and help with inflammation
post-workout so there's a lot going on
here you get the pump you get the
vascularity you get that extra blood
flow yours get some stuff to help with
post workout recovery and it is all
natural with no artificial ingredients
[Music]
foreign
territory here with the supplementation
we want to talk about testosterone
boosting supplements so first of all if
you have concerns about your
testosterone level that's the kind of
thing you need to talk to a doctor for
and get your levels checked uh that's
like the most important step to take
there are some nutrients and extracts
and so on out there in nature that have
been found in some research to support
healthy testosterone levels so some
people like to try out products like
this which is our favorite test booster
this is testofuels testosterone booster
right so what this has here a good
example is vitamin D it's got 500 the
recommended intake and like vitamin D
there's very solid research suggesting
that if you're deficient in vitamin D
which a good amount of people are then
testosterone production can be hampered
so that can help to bring that back to
normal Baseline levels you've also got
zinc as well which has like pretty good
links with people who are deficient in
zinc having impaired testosterone
production so these are nutrients that
can help with testosterone production
right there's also some other kind of
like natural plant extracts that have
some interesting research supporting it
so Tesla fuel here for example it has a
boron and diaspatic acid both are very
very very common in testosterone
boosting supplements across the industry
you've also got some oyster extract here
which might promote testosterone
synthesis and there's also maca root as
well which is a very very common
ingredient as well especially for folks
who are concerned about like their sperm
count and libido you'll often find macro
in those supplements one more time
you've got to talk to your doctor if you
really are concerned about your hormone
levels because this is like really
bordering on you know medical condition
but if you're looking for more natural
non-prescription methods for potentially
putting testosterone it is definitely
worth in our opinion of all the
testosterone promoting supplements out
there check out Testo fuel take it then
see how you feel it might do the trick
next up a really common supplement
increasingly sorrow is carnitine sounds
gonna do my accent carnitine if you're
looking for a carnitine supplement we
really like caged L-Carnitine so
carnitine you got the you got the
creatine the beta Allen all these other
ends as well citrulline beta in
carnitine is uh it's not so much a
pre-workout product even though a lot of
those ingredients are not dependent on
timing uh carnitine is like kind of more
of an anytime supplement that people
tend to take why do people take
carnitine uh it has an array of
potential benefits associated with body
composition right so it seems to be able
to potentially help to transport like
fatty acids into the mitochondria to
help the mitochondria to use fat as fuel
planting is pretty common it's often
seen in fat burning supplements but in
addition to the fat loss potential there
like as far as like helping with fat
oxidation it also is a recovery tool as
well so there there are some interesting
evidence testing that uh it can help
with like preserving muscle like present
preventing or slowing muscle breakdown
and also for helping with post-workout
soreness so in the in the world of
Athletics and strength Athletics in
which we operate a lot here at bar Ben
there are plenty of people who take
carotene most often you hear them saying
they take it from muscle soreness and
for helping the muscle to repair itself
basically after a workout so Claritin
pretty cool supplement pretty
interesting stuff I encourage you to
check it out and uh caged L-Carnitine
pills these is our favorite version of
cartoon on the market
foreign
[Music]
supplement for muscle growth now if you
are new to the world of supplementation
Fitness diet and so on the idea of a
carbohydrate supplement might sound kind
of crazy to you but if you have ever
tracked your calories and macronutrients
before with the goal of gaining muscle
then you have probably thought about the
benefits of a carbohydrate supplement
before long story short if you are
eating to gain muscle you are almost
certainly eating at least one gram of
carbohydrate per gram of protein and you
are probably eating two three maybe even
four grams of carbs per gram of protein
what that means is eating carbohydrates
can get pretty old pretty quickly it
sounds exciting on day one and by day
four you're getting pretty sick of
trying to find new ways to cram
carbohydrates into your diet so a
carbohydrate supplement is not a
terrible idea and a lot of people have
asked the industry for one before and
what we have here is the carb powder
from transparent Labs what we like about
this for one transparent Labs is a
really good company right like they have
uh they're very transparent like that's
what the name suggests so they always
tell you the exact amount of each of the
ingredients in the supplements or no
proprietary Blends and if you're on the
website every ingredient they have
they're like a study attached to it like
telling you why they included it and why
they include that amount of it so we
like that so class addiction is pretty
interesting transparent Labs
clustodextrin we really like this
product because the more on this one's
all naturally flavored and sweetened so
there's no yeah artificial flavors or
sweetness in this uh the carbohydrate
here it's not like regular sugar like
cluster dextrin if you have like a drink
full of clustodextrin it doesn't spike
your blood sugar the way that just
having like a sugary beverage does it
has like a slower onset in that regard
so that's the reason why a lot of people
prefer it to like you know sugary
beverages right so you're not just like
drinking a whole bunch of cane sugar it
is naturally flavored and sweetened you
don't feel bloated and it digests very
quickly so if you are having to get
hundreds and hundreds of grams of
carbohydrates in a day this is a really
easy way to like sip it get up as many
cup carbohydrates as you want and you
won't feel like gross heavy or
hyperactive afterwards so yeah class
detection is pretty cool and our
favorite carb supplement definitely carb
powder from transparent labs
[Music]
that does it for our all-time list of
favorite supplements for muscle growth
uh there's a lot here and a lot of
different types of supplements and like
we've walked through like 10 different
Industries within the supplement realm
during this video I can appreciate it's
been a lot to take in and a lot to
digest the main like I think things to
consider when looking for supplements
for muscle growth I mean number one be
reasonable with your expectations right
because the most important thing I
understood this before and I'll say it
again
your calories your macronutrients your
sleep your workouts these are more
important than supplements that said for
one your calories your macronutrients
that can indeed be improved by like say
a protein supplement or a carbohydrate
supplement right or a meal replacement
powder if that's something you want to
sit in so supplements can indeed be very
useful at filling out your Macros and
your calories but the point is that the
bigger picture of calories
macronutrients that going to start
sticking to that like regardless of
supplements is going to do more for you
supplements that help you to get more
work in at the gym can have a
significant impact on your muscle growth
as well right be realistic with your
expectations and understand that like
while carbohydrates and protein are
great the further down the line you get
the less research there is like
promising you big results and if they do
cause results the smaller the results
are going to beat right like getting
that protein big results having some
diaspatic acid for a temporary boost in
testosterone there's also going to be
smaller so basically find out where
these supplements fit into your overall
plan and lastly talk to your doctor
about out your plan so let's look in and
like the route you're planning to take
and it kind of supplements you're
planning to take as well so that you get
individual advice that's tail to you all
right that does it for our video on the
best supplements for muscle growth again
we have a written version of this video
if you want to check that out taking it
you're on speed and they get a really
close longing look at those nutrition
labels uh if you want to do that just go
to Google write in bar Ben best
supplements for muscle growth and it'll
come right up that's it our video is
totally over I hope you enjoyed it and
we'll catch you for the next one
foreign
[Music]